<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>werk.statt.codes</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on werk.statt.codes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Roland Schmidt &lt;a href=&#39;https://twitter.com/zoowalk&#39; style=&#39;color:gray&#39;&gt;@zoowalk&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Covid-19/Corona Virus in Austria: Updates on data</title>
      <link>/post/covid-19-corona-virus-quick-look-at-some-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/covid-19-corona-virus-quick-look-at-some-data/</guid>
      <description>Graphs updated on Sunday, 29 Mar 2020
With the COVID epidemic taking a pretty firm grip on our lives, I thought I’ll use this post as a kind of analytic repository regarding the developments in Austria. There are certainly plenty of other, more advanced analyses out there, so see this as a kind of personal attempt to get a grip on the virus and what is happening around us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bosnia: Voting behavior in the House of Peoples (2014-2018)</title>
      <link>/post/bosnia-house-of-peoples/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/bosnia-house-of-peoples/</guid>
      <description>Site might be best viewed on a desktop computer, rather than mobile device.
CONTEXTThis blog post is a continuation of the analysis of voting behavior in Bosnia’s parliament during the 2014 to 2018 legislative period. In a previous post, I looked primarily into the lower chamber, the House of Representatives. This post now deals with the upper chamber, the House of Peoples (HoP, dom naroda).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Segregation in Vienna&#39;s primary schools?</title>
      <link>/post/primary-schools-in-vienna/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/primary-schools-in-vienna/</guid>
      <description>ContextOur daughter will turn six this summer and in Austria this means that she will start attending school in autumn. While in most parts of Austria’s countryside it’s a rather foregone conclusion to which school a new pupil will go (since there is mostly only one school ‘in town’), choosing a school for your kid in a city like Vienna can become a somewhat protracted decision making process with numerous schools in the vicinity to select from.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bosnia: Voting behavior of MPs in the House of Representatives</title>
      <link>/post/bih-voting-behavior-of-mps-in-house-of-representatives/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/bih-voting-behavior-of-mps-in-house-of-representatives/</guid>
      <description>CONTEXTA while ago I noticed that the website of Bosnia’s parliament also provides the voting records for each separate vote taken in both houses. These records also include the voting behavior for each individual MP. Here an example of one of these voting records:
While the dominant role of the ethnic cleavage in Bosnian politics has been a constant theme and continuously emphasized for the last 25 years (to an extent which frequently blanks out other salient issues), I hadn’t seen any empirical record on MP’s individual voting behavior which could corroborate the cleavage’s prevalence in the legislative arena (one insightful exception is Birgit Bahtić-Kunrath’s 2011 paper).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bosnia: Voting behavior of MPs in the House of Representatives - part 2</title>
      <link>/post/bih-voting-behavior-of-mps-in-house-of-representatives-part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/bih-voting-behavior-of-mps-in-house-of-representatives-part2/</guid>
      <description>Entity vetoArticle IV 3(d)
‘All decisions in both chambers shall be by majority of those present and voting. The Delegates and Members shall make their best efforts to see that the majority includes at least one-third of the votes of Delegates or Members from the territory of each Entity. If a majority vote does not include one-third of the votes of Delegates or Members from the territory of each Entity, the Chair and Deputy Chairs shall meet as a commission and attempt to obtain approval within three days of the vote.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Austrian General Elections 2019: Preference votes</title>
      <link>/post/vorzugsstimmen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/vorzugsstimmen/</guid>
      <description>ContextOn 29 September, Austria held its general elections to the national assembly (Nationalrat). By now a flurry of analyses and comments has been published and the caravan of political commentary has largely moved on, at least when it comes to the analysis of the results itself (the government formation train is finally also getting up to speed). One aspect, I personally have never looked into, and which seems to fall a bit under the radar, is the use of preference votes by Austria’s electorate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women in parliament</title>
      <link>/post/women-in-parliament/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/women-in-parliament/</guid>
      <description>ContextSo, Austria has a new parliament. Following the elections in September, the new lower house got constituted yesterday and as a few noted it is more diverse than previous ones. Here’s a nice visualization if you want to get a quick overview. Among others, it was the share of women in parliament which was particularly often noted. None of Austria’s previous lower houses had an as high share of women at the start of a new legislative period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link to previous posts</title>
      <link>/post/link-to-previous-posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/link-to-previous-posts/</guid>
      <description>Earlier ramblings were collected on my RPubs file. I’ll gradually move theme to this site, but till then they remain available here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Not that the world would have been waiting for another blog&amp;hellip; but there you go. This (work in progress?) blog is a collection of my &amp;lsquo;thoughts in R&amp;rsquo; with varying degrees of seriousness. Posts will mostly relate to my substantive interests (comparative political science, human rights) or are simply notes to myself on a specific R function. Not claiming any final truth. One step at a time.
Roland Schmidt #IStandWithCEU #CYG</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>European Parliament Elections 2019: Facebook ads of Austrian candidates</title>
      <link>/post/european-parliament-elections-2019-facebook-ads-of-austrian-candidates/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/european-parliament-elections-2019-facebook-ads-of-austrian-candidates/</guid>
      <description>For the analysis of the use of political ads on facebook in the run-up to the European Parliament elections 2019 in Austria see here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>