<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on werk.statt.codes</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on werk.statt.codes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Roland Schmidt &lt;a href=&#39;https://twitter.com/zoowalk&#39; style=&#39;color:gray&#39;&gt;@zoowalk&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Potential sizing issue when importing interactive plots (ggraph; htmlWidget)</title>
      <link>/post/size-interactive-plots/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/size-interactive-plots/</guid>
      <description>This post documents a potential issue when it comes to sizing interactive images/htmlwidgets produced with the ggiraph and htmlwidgets packages. The goal is to import interactive graphs produced in other R(Studio) Projects into a blogdown post. I assume/hope there there is a relatively easy solution to it, but I haven’t yet figured it out.
Create interactive plotFirst, let’s create an interactive plot. Here it has the dimensions 7 by 7 inches and is meant to have no padding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women in parliament</title>
      <link>/post/women-in-parliament/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/women-in-parliament/</guid>
      <description>ContextSo, Austria has a new parliament. Following the elections in September, the new lower house got constituted yesterday and as a few noted it is more diverse than previous ones. Here’s a nice visualization if you want to get a quick overview. Among others, it was the share of women in parliament which was particularly often noted. None of Austria’s previous lower houses had an as high share of women at the start of a new legislative period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link to previous posts</title>
      <link>/post/link-to-previous-posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/link-to-previous-posts/</guid>
      <description>Earlier ramblings were collected on my RPubs file. I’ll gradually move theme to this site, but till then they remain available at here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Austrian General Elections 2019: Preference votes</title>
      <link>/post/vorzugsstimmen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/vorzugsstimmen/</guid>
      <description>ContextOn 29 September, Austria held its general elections to the national assembly (Nationalrat). By now a flurry of analyses and comments has been published and the caravan of political commentary has largely moved on, at least when it comes to the analysis of the results itself (and government formation train finally also getting up to speed). One aspect, I personally have never looked into, and which seems to fall a bit under the radar, is the use of preference votes by Austria’s electorate.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>