<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OCR on werk.statt.codes</title>
    <link>/tags/ocr/</link>
    <description>Recent content in OCR on werk.statt.codes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Roland Schmidt &lt;a href=&#39;https://twitter.com/zoowalk&#39; style=&#39;color:gray&#39;&gt;@zoowalk&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/ocr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Austrian Parliament: MPs transparency and conflict of interest report - Bundesrat</title>
      <link>/post/austrian-parliament-mps-transparency-and-conflict-of-interest-report-bundesrat/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/austrian-parliament-mps-transparency-and-conflict-of-interest-report-bundesrat/</guid>
      <description>ContextThis is a follow-up on my previous post on the transprancey report by Austria’s Parliament. While I limited
Steps in RSetupCode: Load packages
library(tidyverse)library(here)library(extrafont)loadfonts(device = &amp;quot;win&amp;quot;, quiet = T)library(hrbrthemes)hrbrthemes::update_geom_font_defaults(family = &amp;quot;Roboto Condensed&amp;quot;,size=3)library(scales)library(knitr)library(paletteer)library(ggtext)library(glue)library(gt)library(DT)library(pdftools)library(lemon)library(gender)library(ggiraph)library(rvest)Code: Define rmarkdown options</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Austrian Parliament: MPs transparency and conflict of interest report</title>
      <link>/post/austrian-parliament-mps-transparency-and-conflict-of-interest-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/austrian-parliament-mps-transparency-and-conflict-of-interest-report/</guid>
      <description>ContextRecently, at the end of June, the Austrian Parliament published its annual report on MPs’ additional sources of revenue and pertaining activities (see here). The publication is mandatory by law, and basically seeks to curtail potential conflicts of interest and to increase transparency as to MPs’ activities outside of parliament. While the list comes, unsurprisingly, with a number of caveats 1, and by itself can hardly constitute a watertight safeguard against the various ‘undemocratic temptations’, the report nevertheless seems to provide interesting data on MPs’ financial statuses and professional machinations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bosnia: Voting behavior in the House of Peoples (2014-2018)</title>
      <link>/post/bosnia-house-of-peoples/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/bosnia-house-of-peoples/</guid>
      <description>Site might be best viewed on a desktop computer, rather than mobile device.
CONTEXTThis blog post has been lingering for a few months now in my draft folder and for no other tangible reason than the Covid19 mayhem, I have no excuse for not having posted it much earlier. In short, the blog is a continuation of the analysis of voting behavior in Bosnia’s parliament during the 2014 to 2018 legislative period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bosnia: Voting behavior of MPs in the House of Representatives</title>
      <link>/post/bih-voting-behavior-of-mps-in-house-of-representatives/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/bih-voting-behavior-of-mps-in-house-of-representatives/</guid>
      <description>CONTEXTA while ago I noticed that the website of Bosnia’s parliament also provides the voting records for each separate vote taken in both houses. These records also include the voting behavior for each individual MP. Here an example of one of these voting records:
While the dominant role of the ethnic cleavage in Bosnian politics has been a constant theme and continuously emphasized for the last 25 years (to an extent which frequently blanks out other salient issues), I hadn’t seen any empirical record on MP’s individual voting behavior which could corroborate the cleavage’s prevalence in the legislative arena (one insightful exception is Birgit Bahtić-Kunrath’s 2011 paper).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>