<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>web scraping on werk.statt.codes</title>
    <link>https://werk.statt.codes/tags/web-scraping/</link>
    <description>Recent content in web scraping on werk.statt.codes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Roland Schmidt &lt;a href=&#39;https://twitter.com/zoowalk&#39; style=&#39;color:gray&#39;&gt;@zoowalk&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://werk.statt.codes/tags/web-scraping/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Austrian Parliament: MPs transparency and conflict of interest report</title>
      <link>https://werk.statt.codes/post/austrian-parliament-mps-transparency-and-conflict-of-interest-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://werk.statt.codes/post/austrian-parliament-mps-transparency-and-conflict-of-interest-report/</guid>
      <description>ContextRecently, at the end of June, the Austrian Parliament published its annual report on MPs’ additional sources of revenue and pertaining activities (see here). The publication is mandatory by law, and basically seeks to curtail potential conflicts of interest and to increase transparency as to MPs’ activities outside of parliament. While the list comes, unsurprisingly, with a number of caveats 1, and by itself can hardly constitute a watertight safeguard against the various ‘undemocratic temptations’, the report nevertheless seems to provide interesting data on MPs’ financial statuses and professional machinations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bosnia: Voting behavior of MPs in the House of Representatives</title>
      <link>https://werk.statt.codes/post/bih-voting-behavior-of-mps-in-house-of-representatives/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://werk.statt.codes/post/bih-voting-behavior-of-mps-in-house-of-representatives/</guid>
      <description>CONTEXTA while ago I noticed that the website of Bosnia’s parliament also provides the voting records for each separate vote taken in both houses. These records also include the voting behavior for each individual MP. Here an example of one of these voting records:
While the dominant role of the ethnic cleavage in Bosnian politics has been a constant theme and continuously emphasized for the last 25 years (to an extent which frequently blanks out other salient issues), I hadn’t seen any empirical record on MP’s individual voting behavior which could corroborate the cleavage’s prevalence in the legislative arena (one insightful exception is Birgit Bahtić-Kunrath’s 2011 paper).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>